{
    "id": "febc10cae515411188250ab7f8adfcd7",
    "title": "Comparative and Superlatives Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "03e0ee5502ce4e629658e711f14d86a3",
            "title": "Comparatives and Superlatives",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "The coat was ......................... than I thought.",
                    "description": "We use the comparative form of the adjective before than.",
                    "answers": [
                        "more expensive",
                        "most expensive",
                        "the most expensive",
                        "the more expensive"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Canada is ......................... India.",
                    "description": "Adjectives of one or two syllables form their comparative forms by adding -er to the positive adjective. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "bigger then",
                        "bigger than",
                        "more big than"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He is not ................................. his brother.",
                    "description": "When we make comparisons using the positive adjective, we use the structure as...as...",
                    "answers": [
                        "as successful as",
                        "more successful as",
                        "as successful than"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Greenland is ......................... island in the world.",
                    "description": "The superlative adjective is used when we compare one thing with the group to which it belongs. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "largest",
                        "the largest",
                        "larger",
                        "the larger"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You are ............................... person I have met.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "most interesting",
                        "the most interesting",
                        "the more interesting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is ............................ film I have ever watched.",
                    "description": "Here we are comparing one film with all the films, and therefore a superlative adjective is used. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "best",
                        "the best",
                        "better",
                        "the better"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am not very hungry so I will give you the ....................... steak.",
                    "description": "When a group has only two members, we can use either the comparative or the superlative however, the comparative is considered more appropriate here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "bigger",
                        "biggest",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is ........................... carpet I have seen.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "dirtiest",
                        "the dirtiest",
                        "dirtyest"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She solved the puzzle ............................. than everybody else.",
                    "description": "Either quicker or more quickly is possible here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "quickly",
                        "quicker",
                        "more quickly",
                        "more quicker"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I would be ............................ if I had more chin.",
                    "description": "Some compound adjectives like good-looking have two possible comparatives. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "more good-looking",
                        "better-looking",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Thank you very much. That was ........................... of you.",
                    "description": "Most can be used with adjectives to mean 'very'. So the sentence 'That was most kind of you' means 'That was very kind of you'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "most kind",
                        "the kindest",
                        "kinder",
                        "All of the above"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You are .......................... your mother than your father.",
                    "description": "'Like' always has more and most. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "more like",
                        "liker",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}